BERTRAND DUBAUT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - RUBY DEVELOPER

bdubaut@gmail.com +31 6 80 10 13 79

I'm a French software engineer living in Amsterdam, Netherlands. I am 28, speak fluent English, and have a Master's degree in Computer Science from one of the top French Computer Engineering schools.

I enjoy working surrounded by brilliant people as I see the opportunity to always improve my skills and knowledge. I am a Ruby developer (Ruby on Rails, Grape) with a strong interest in Elixir. I have been building Rails applications and REST APIs for 4 years, and I strongly believe in TDD and BDD. I strive to always be learning new concepts and technologies.

On a more personal note, I have played baseball my whole life, including one year of college Baseball in California.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING RUBY RUBY ON RAILS GRAPE API FRAMEWORK ELIXIR JAVA JAVASCRIPT COFFEESCRIPT JQUERY HTML 5 CSS

DATABASES MYSQL POSTGRESQL MONGODB REDIS ORMS ACTIVERECORD MONGOID

CLOUD AWS S3 REDSHIFT EC2

PROJECT AGILE PROJECT MANAGEMENT GITHUB FLOW

EMPLOYMENT

Lead Software Engineer, Mila Industries, B.V.

2016-06 — Present

Mila is a smart contact manager that integrates with the tools you use for your business. Ruby Ruby on Rails Aurelia JS MongoDB PostgreSQL Workflow

Software Engineer - Ruby developper, Everydayhero

2015-08 — 2016-03

Everydayhero is a crowdfunding platform aimed at charity fundraising.

Ruby Ruby on Rails Elixir PostgreSQL React AWS

Software Engineer, Oomph

2014-09 — 2015-07

Oomph is a platform for publishers and advertisers allowing them to create digital magazines or ads for mobile devices and tablets.

Ruby Ruby on Rails AWS PostgreSQL

2014-01 — 2014-07

Visibleo is a web-marketing start-up based in the Paris Suburbs. They perform Facebook Ads and Google AdWords campaigns, while also creating websites for their clients. In charge of creating and developing web applications for the IT department of the company.

Ruby Ruby on Rails AWS Grape API JQuery MongoDB

Technical Project Manager/Developer, Reputation Squad

2013-02 — 2013-09

Reputation Squad is an E-Reputation agency in Paris: the company manages and monitors its clients' reputation on the Internet. In charge of creating and developing web and social media monitoring tools for the agency

Ruby on Rails PHP Perl Facebook API Twitter API Project Management

Technical consultant / Developer, Sogeti

2011-02 — 2013-02

Consultant in projects for several large-scale French companies like Air France or Renault.

 Managed a developer team based in India from France Java/J2EE Oracle SQL HP Quality Center QuickTest Pro Visual Basic

PROJECTS

Adomatic

Solution to convert an existing print Ad inventory into engaging rich media Ads for tablet and mobile. Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL AWS

Global Sourcing Renault

In charge of a vehicle selling application for RENAULT's employees (as a consultant with Sogeti). Technical specifications, and management of an Off-Shore development team in India. Also testing, deployement actions, bug management.

Java/J2EE Oracle SQL WebSphere

Air France Check-In

Development and maintenance of a test automaton for the new passenger check-in system for Air France and SkyTeam (KLM, Alitalia....). Discussions with the KLM dev team to help them develop their own automaton. The automaton was designed to take over every interface (Desk, Internet portal, self check-in). HP Quick Test Pro Visual Basic

Paris Universite Club Baseball web app

Design, implementation, deployment of a web app for the Paris Baseball Softball and Cricket club. Providing blogs, emails and player management tools for the amateur club Ruby on Rails Devise Heroku Mandrill Refills/Bitters RSS Ghost

EDUCATION

Master's degree of computer science and software engineering, Ecole advanced C 2011-09 — 2013-06 des Technologies Numeriques Appliquees programming Java PHP Ruby .NET Object-Oriented programming

Bachelor's degree of computer science and software engineering, Shell C 2010-09 — 2011-06 Ecole des Technologies Numeriques Appliquees programming PHP MySQL UNIX System Administration Networks

Undergraduate studies, Universite Paris VI Linear Algebra Algorithms OCaml C Programming 2009-09 — 2010-06

Undergraduate studies, Merced Community College Political Science Chemistry Calculus

Baseball English 2008-09 — 2009-06

Undergraduate studies, Universite Paris VI Linear Algebra Chemistry Physics Calculus C Programming 2006-09 — 2008-06

AFFILIATION

Player, Youth Coach, Team Captain, Paris Universite Club Baseball

1995-09 — 2015-08

This is the club I grew up with, playing, coaching the kids, and ultimately being the club captain of the first team of Paris' baseball club.

Player, Youth Coach, Windsor Royals Baseball Club

2015-09 — Present

Playing competitive baseball for the best club in Brisbane, and teaching the game to the younger generation.

Instructor, Brisbane Baseball Academy

2015-10 — Present

Teaching Brisbane's top baseball talent how to improve their game.

Member, Merced Blue Devils Alumni Association

2010-01 — Present

REFERENCES

Contact details will be provided if requested.

Raoul Wissink, CTO
Raoul is the current CTO of Mila

Jennifer Ho, Developer & Content manager Jenny is a junior developer and head of content for Mila.

Jasmyn Mason, HR manager Jasmyn is the HR manager for EverydayHero.

John May, Ruby/Haskell/iOS developer John and I worked together at Oomph. John now lives in Amsterdam as well.

Ryan Booker, Ruby/iOS developer Ryan and I worked together for Oomph and EverydayHero.

Valerie Abbot, QA Manager

Valerie hired me to work for Oomph when I first arrived in Australia.